CONTACT

C

+91 9361561324



asuryaselvi98@gmail.com



No 3/101, muduchur, Tambaram, Chennai, 600048.

EDUCATION

B. Sc., 2018 | CGPA 8 Information Technology

YADAVA COLLEGE. Madurai, TamilNadu.

SKILLS

Language/Frameworks:

Core-Java, MySQL, TestNG, BDD Cucumber, JUnit, POM, Data-Driven, Appium

- Bug Tracking Tool: JIRA
- Automation Tools:
 Selenium, Play-Wright, Appium
- Build Management Tool: Maven
- Source Management Tool: GitHub
- CICD:

Jenkins

API Testing:

Postman, Rest Assured

- IDE:

Eclipse

EDUCATION

ENGLISH TAMIL

SURYADEVI. A

SOFTWARE TEST_ENGINEER

ABOUT ME

Enthusiastic and highly skilled technical and testing professional with overall 4+ years of experience in the IT industry. To work in an ambitious environment where I can efficiently deliver my technical knowledge, problem-solving skills, and interpersonal skills to enrich the organization. Currently looking for a new opportunity to work with an innovative company in a progressive and challenging environment.

■ CORE COMPETENCIES

- Having 4+ years of outstanding experience in Software Testing
- Tremendous expertise creating Selenium Web-Driver automation scripts in Core Java.
- Adequate knowledge of the Agile and Scrum software testing methodology.
- Proven track record in creating test plans and test cases.
- Experience and expertise in Java programming and OOPS concepts.
- Has experience with the Cucumber BDD framework, TestNG.
- Expert in creating reusable functional framework components and creating POM using the Page Factory Concept, Junit Framework and testing management expertise.
- Maven builds tool and GIT version control experience.
- Very familiar with JIRA.
- Expertise in understanding and analyzing test requirements, tracking changes, and maintaining test requirements.
- Experience with data-driven testing
- Excellent Knowledge of the Software Testing Life Cycle (STLC)
- Basic Knowledge in Postman Tool, Rest assured
- Experience in writing CSS Selectors, Xpath Expressions to identify Web Elements
- Excellent grasp of basic SQL.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Techdeva Infotech
Software Test Engineer

Feb 2023 to Present

e Test Engineer Chennai

TNQ TECHNOLOGIES
Senior Associate

Sep 2018 to Jul 2022 Chennai

PROJECTS HANDLED

PROJECT 3

Kohls

Domain : E- Commerce **Duration** : Feb 2023 to Present

Description

Kohl's is a well-known department store chain in the United States, offering a wide range of products, including clothing, footwear, accessories, home goods, beauty products, and more. They cater to a diverse customer base, from fashion-conscious individuals to families looking for affordable and stylish items.

PROJECT 2

Fun Express

Domain : E-Commerce **Duration** : Dec 2020-Jul 2022

Description

Fun Express is an online retail destination known for its wide selection of party supplies, toys, novelties, and entertaining products. Whether you're planning a birthday party, a special event, or looking for fun items for various occasions, Fun Express offers a diverse range of products to add excitement and enjoyment to your celebrations. Their website provides a convenient shopping experience, allowing customers to browse and purchase items that make parties and gatherings memorable and enjoyable.

PROJECT 1

Kroger

Domain: E-Commerce **Duration: Jun 2019 - Nov 2020**

Description

Kroger is an online store of choice among Americans buying groceries. Kroger also offers excellent discounts on foodstuff through daily and weekly online special offers and sales. This online store provides discount codes and coupons that help you save money.

Roles and Responsibilities

- Developed 100+ test plans and test cases.
- Reviewed- 50 user interfaces for functionality and adherence to design guidelines.
- Executed test cases across 15+ functional product areas, beating team efficiency averages by 20% against work completion deadlines.
- Drafted test reports, reducing data key insights that helped increase team efficiency by 31%.
- Collaborated with 3 software development engineers to build a dead understanding of features and architecture prior to testing.
- Involvement in all Agile Ceremonies like Sprint Planning, Sprint Grooming, Scrum Call, Sprint Review and Sprint Retrospective meeting.
- Developed frameworks like BBD cucumber, Junit testing as per the functionality requirements.
- Maintained Codes through Version Control System GIT.
- Performed Cross browser testing and parallel execution to check the compatibility and stability of the application.
- Performed compatability testing on channels such as Internet Explorer, Google Chrome and Edge browser.
- Involved in Bug fixing for the defects and test them in various environment on the application used by live production team.

Roles and Responsibilities

- Involved in the analysis, design, and construction phases of the project.
- Prepared and executed Test Cases and captured Test Results and reported bugs to developer.
- Performed System Testing, Smoke Testing, Functional, and Regression
- Assigned the tasks of preparing test scripts and performing Black-box testing.
- Prepared daily status reports as per the planned and actual progress of deliverables.
- Provided Knowledge Transfer to new members of the project team.
- Developing and Maintaining Automated test scripts for Web Applications using Core Java with Selenium Webdriver.
- Create, enhance, and maintain the automation framework using BDD Cucumber to ensure scalability, reusability, and maintainability of test scripts.
- Integrate Automation scripts into the pipeline to enable automated execution on code commits.
- Responsible for automation code maintenance on Team Foundation Server for various environments.
- Executed the test scripts and reported the defects through defect tracking tool JIRA.

Roles and Responsibilities

- Understood business requirements.
- Involved in the analysis, design, and construction phases of the project.
- Prepared and executed Test Cases and captured Test Results and reported bugs to developer.
- Assigned the tasks of preparing test scripts and perform Black-box testing.
- Prepared daily status reports as per the planned and actual progress of deliverable.
- Provided Knowledge Transfer to new members of the project team.
- Direct interaction with Client Business team for various gueries.
- Implemented UI part Automation using Selenium with Core Java and TestNG.
- Responsible for automation code maintenance on Team Foundation Server for various environments.
- Reviewed test scripts and suggested modifications.
- Executed the test scripts and reported the defects through defect tracking tool JIRA.